<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
    <jcr:content
        cq:lastModified="{Date}2021-02-24T07:32:54.349Z"
        cq:lastModifiedBy="hitesh.raut@abbott.com"
        cq:lastReplicated="{Date}2021-02-24T07:35:36.118Z"
        cq:lastReplicatedBy="hitesh.raut@abbott.com"
        cq:lastReplicationAction="Activate"
        cq:template="/conf/bts/cybersecurity/settings/wcm/templates/tandc"
        jcr:isCheckedOut="{Boolean}true"
        jcr:mixinTypes="[mix:versionable]"
        jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
        jcr:title="Terms of Use"
        jcr:uuid="84d322cc-a53d-411c-80fe-ab62e080bca0"
        sling:resourceType="bts/cybersecurity/components/structure/page"
        badgePosition="top-right"
        badgeRequired="{Boolean}false"
        changeFrequency="always"
        contentCategory="faq"
        hideBreadcrumb="false"
        seeMoreAction="_self"
        seeMoreExternal="false">
        <root
            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
            sling:resourceType="wcm/foundation/components/responsivegrid">
            <responsivegrid
                jcr:created="{Date}2021-01-06T16:17:26.453+05:30"
                jcr:createdBy="admin"
                jcr:lastModified="{Date}2021-01-06T16:23:03.186+05:30"
                jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                sling:resourceType="wcm/foundation/components/responsivegrid">
                <layoutcontainer
                    jcr:created="{Date}2021-01-18T11:47:30.895Z"
                    jcr:createdBy="rakesh.kumar14@abbott.com"
                    jcr:lastModified="{Date}2021-01-18T11:48:05.901Z"
                    jcr:lastModifiedBy="rakesh.kumar14@abbott.com"
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="bts/cybersecurity/components/content/layoutcontainer"
                    containerVariation="variation5">
                    <var5-parsys1 jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured">
                        <text
                            jcr:created="{Date}2021-01-14T15:31:53.993Z"
                            jcr:createdBy="srinivasahanuma.kesireddy@abbott.com"
                            jcr:lastModified="{Date}2021-02-10T10:35:23.478Z"
                            jcr:lastModifiedBy="srinivasahanuma.kesireddy@abbott.com"
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="bts/globals/components/content/text"
                            text="&lt;h4>&lt;strong>LAST UPDATED DECEMBER 18, 2020&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>These Standard Terms and Conditions of Use (“Terms”) govern the access and use of the Cybersecurity Portal (the “Portal”) provided by Abbott Laboratories, with its principal place of business at 100 Abbott Park Road, Abbott Park, Illinois 60064 (“&lt;strong>Abbott&lt;/strong>”).&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Authorized Users may have access to features provided through the Portal, including the ability to view and download Documents to proactively identify vulnerabilities in their Organization’s environment&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>To access and use the Portal, you must comply with applicable law and these Terms as may be revised or updated from time to time by Abbott.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART I – DEFINED TERMS&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>The following terms have the following meaning in these Terms:&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>“&lt;strong>Affiliate&lt;/strong>” means, with respect to a given Entity, any Entity that is directly or indirectly Controlling, Controlled by, or under common Control with such Entity. “&lt;strong>Control&lt;/strong>” and its derivative terms, mean the possession, directly or indirectly, of the power to direct or cause the direction of the management and policies of an Entity. “&lt;strong>Entity&lt;/strong>” means and refers to all forms of legally recognized entities.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>“&lt;strong>Authorized Users&lt;/strong>” means the individuals who are provided with accounts created by Abbott to access and use the functionality of the Portal on behalf of their Organization (as defined herein) as authorized by Abbott&lt;em>. &lt;/em>Abbott assigns access privileges and login credentials to each Authorized User&lt;em>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>“&lt;strong>Confidential Information&lt;/strong>” means information, including the Portal, any and all Documents, trade secrets, know-how, proprietary information, formulae, processes, techniques and information relating to the Disclosing Party’s past, present, and future marketing, financial, research and development activities, and personal information about consumers, patients, employees, shareholders, physicians, Company, consultants, competitors, and customers, that may be disclosed, whether orally or in writing, to the Receiving Party, or that may be otherwise received or accessed by the Receiving Party in connection with the use of the Portal.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>“&lt;strong>Documents&lt;/strong>” means vulnerability and security-related product data or information, including MDS2 Forms and SBOM Forms.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>“&lt;strong>Document Format&lt;/strong>” means a human and machine readable format, including PDF and XML format.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>“&lt;strong>Portal&lt;/strong>”&lt;strong> &lt;/strong>means the Cybersecurity Portal, which includes a website from which Authorized Users may access and download Documents.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>“&lt;strong>We&lt;/strong>,”&lt;strong> &lt;/strong>“&lt;strong>us&lt;/strong>,”&lt;strong> &lt;/strong>and “&lt;strong>our&lt;/strong>”&lt;strong> &lt;/strong>means Abbott Laboratories&lt;em>. &lt;/em>Nothing in the definition of “we,” “us,” and “our” should be construed as including any Abbott Affiliates as a Party to this Agreement&lt;em>. &lt;/em>“&lt;strong>Parties&lt;/strong>” means You and us (each of which individually is a “&lt;strong>Party&lt;/strong>”).&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>“&lt;strong>You&lt;/strong>” means an Authorized User accessing the Portal on behalf of an Organization.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART II – ACCEPTANCE OF TERMS&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>By accessing and using the Portal, including viewing or downloading any Documents accessible via the Portal, You, accept these Terms and any applicable &lt;strong>&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abbott.com/privacy-policy.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>Abbott privacy policy&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>, which is hereby incorporated into these Terms. You are responsible for reviewing these Terms from time to time for applicable changes.&amp;nbsp; By using the Portal after changes to the Terms have been made, You are indicating your acceptance of those changes. In some cases, we may ask You to affirmatively confirm agreement with these Terms or changes to these Terms on behalf of yourself and the Organization.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>In the event of a conflict between these Terms and any other terms You may be required to accept to access and use this Portal, these Terms shall control to the extent of the conflict.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>WHEN YOU ACCEPT THESE TERMS, YOU AGREE TO THEM ON YOUR INDIVIDUAL BEHALF AND ON BEHALF OF THE ORGANIZATION BY WHICH YOU ARE EMPLOYED OR ENGAGED AND FOR WHOSE BENEFIT YOU ARE USING THE PORTAL (“&lt;strong>ORGANIZATION&lt;/strong>”). YOU REPRESENT AND WARRANT THAT YOU (A) HAVE READ AND UNDERSTAND THESE TERMS, (B) ARE OF A LEGAL AGE TO ENTER INTO A BINDING AGREEMENT, AND (C) ARE AUTHORIZED BY THE ORGANIZATION TO AGREE TO THE TERMS ON ITS BEHALF.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>You and your Organization are responsible and liable for any non-compliance with these Terms by You or any individual or third party who received unauthorized access to this Portal as a result of any action or inaction by You.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART III – TERM AND TERMINATION&lt;/strong>&lt;span>&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>These Terms shall remain effective until terminated. We may immediately terminate these Terms and/or suspend your right to access and use the Portal at any time for any reason, including if You fail to comply with any provision of these Terms. Upon termination, all rights granted to You by these Terms will terminate.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART IV – ACCOUNT RESPONSIBILITY&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Responsibility for Authorized User Accounts&lt;/u>. Abbott is solely responsible for creating Authorized User accounts for individuals identified by the Organization as needing access and use rights to the Portal.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>You and the Organization are responsible for and assume liability with respect to any and all actions by You or any other individuals using your account credentials (which is strictly prohibited under these Terms), non-compliance with these Terms, and for the consequences of any breach of security of an Authorized User account or your account credentials. You acknowledge that we may review and audit the access to and use of the Portal (including tracking any prohibited distribution of any Documents) by Authorized Users for compliance with these Terms or as otherwise required or permitted by applicable law.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Maintaining and Safeguarding Authorized Users Credentials&lt;/u>. You will not permit anyone to access and use the Portal on your behalf. You will ensure your Authorized User profile information is kept up to date. You will immediately notify Abbott when you are no longer employed or engaged by the Organization, or whenever you no longer require access to the Portal in connection with your duties and responsibilities to the Organization.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Your Organization must notify Abbott when an Authorized User is no longer employed or engaged by the Organization or otherwise no longer requires access to the Portal.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>You shall take measures to ensure that your Authorized User account credentials are protected and will not be disclosed to any other individual for any reason. If You or we have any basis to believe that an account or account credentials have been compromised, You agree to immediately change the affected password, and immediately notify us at productsecurity@abbott.com that the password should be or has been changed due to a potential compromise. We reserve the right to change account credentials at any time in our sole discretion to protect the Portal, us, and/or others.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Reporting Defects&lt;/u>. You will promptly report to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:productsecurity@abbott.com&quot;>productsecurity@abbott.com&lt;/a> any defects or problems that prevent You or any Authorized User from using the Portal, and You will cooperate with us in addressing or resolving such issues.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Reporting Data Breaches&lt;/u>. You will promptly report to productsecurity@abbott.com any incident or data breach associated with the Portal that You observe or reasonably suspect, and You will fully cooperate with us, law enforcement, or any other applicable regulatory authority in addressing the incident or breach.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Responsibility for Third Party Services and Software&lt;/u>. You or your organization will be responsible for obtaining and maintaining any internet connections, computing equipment, supplies, third-party software, and personnel necessary for You to access and use the Portal&lt;em>. &lt;/em>The Portal may require the use of the software provided by unaffiliated third parties (e.g., a web browser and Adobe PDF viewer) (“&lt;strong>Third-Party Software&lt;/strong>”) to enable the full functionality of the Portal. Your use of Third-Party Software shall be subject to the applicable terms and conditions set forth by the providers of such Third-Party Software, and You shall comply with such terms and conditions and, if applicable, pay fees for the use of such Third-Party Software. We disclaim all responsibilities, warranties, and liabilities relating to the use of Third-Party Software.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>You may only use the Documents provided through this Portal in connection with Third-Party Software (including any automation tools or software) to proactively identify and mitigate vulnerabilities in your Organization’s environment. You may not, directly, or indirectly, use any Third-Party Software to exploit Abbott product vulnerabilities or allow others to exploit Abbott product vulnerabilities.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART V – ACCESS AND USE RIGHTS&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>In exchange for Your promises and performance of these Terms, we will provide you a limited, revocable, non-transferable, non-sublicensable license to access and use the Portal to view and download Documents to proactively identify vulnerabilities in your Organization’s environment.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Acceptable Use&lt;/u>. Except as expressly permitted by these Terms, You will not and will not permit anyone to:&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(a) access or use the Portal (i) from a jurisdiction where such access or use is not authorized, (ii) for any illegal purpose, or (iii) in violation of any local, state, national, or international law;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(b) copy, alter, or modify the Portal or merge the Portal with any other computer programs;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(c) share, redistribute, copy, alter or modify any Documents viewed or downloaded from the Portal;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(d) access or use Documents or any information or data about the Portal that will allow anyone to use the Documents or Portal to exploit Abbott product vulnerabilities;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(e) use any information or data obtained from the Portal, including from any Documents viewed or downloaded, for any commercial purpose or benefit to You, your Organization, or any third party.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(f) use the Portal to transmit or store infringing, obscene, threatening, or otherwise unlawful or tortious material;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(g) transmit or store material containing malicious or harmful code;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(h) bypass or disable any protections to prevent access to any unauthorized aspect of the Service;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(i) rent, license, lease, distribute, sell, assign, or otherwise transfer rights to the Portal IP;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(j) circumvent any access control or digital rights management measures or technology associated with the Portal IP;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(k) remove, alter, or obscure any intellectual property marking, license notice or any other disclosures or terms from the Portal or any Documents;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(l) misuse or abuse the Portal, or interfere with or disrupt the integrity or performance of the Portal or data contained therein;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(m) use scrapers, robots, or other data gathering devices not provided by us on or through the Portal;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(n) conduct activities that may be harmful to others or that could damage Abbott’s reputation;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(o) violate, or encourage others to violate, any right of a third party, including by infringing or misappropriating any third-party intellectual property right, or violating any third-party privacy right;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(p) perform any fraudulent activity including impersonating any person or entity, claiming a false affiliation or accreditation, accessing any other Portal account without permission, or falsifying Your account registration information;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(q) allow the Portal to be used in any way whatsoever by unauthorized individuals;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(r) redistribute any Portal Documents; or&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(s) attempt to do any of the foregoing acts.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Notification of Non-Compliance with Acceptable Use Requirements&lt;/u>. You agree to promptly report to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:productsecurity@abbott.com&quot;>productsecurity@abbott.com&lt;/a> if You believe that any individual or entity has or is reasonably likely to have engaged in any of the activities set forth in the foregoing Section V(8)(a) through (s).&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART VI – CONFIDENTIALITY OBLIGATIONS&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&amp;nbsp;(a) The Parties agree that the obligations of confidentiality shall survive termination or expiration of these Terms indefinitely. Either Party may be given access to Confidential Information (“Receiving Party”) of the other Party (“Disclosing Party”). Notwithstanding the foregoing, except with respect to personal information, Confidential Information shall not include information (i) previously known to the Receiving Party, as evidenced by written records, without an obligation of confidentiality; (ii) independently developed by or for the Receiving Party, as evidenced by written records, without use or any other processing of the Confidential Information; (iii) acquired by the Receiving Party from a third party which is not, to the Receiving Party’s knowledge, under an obligation of confidentiality with respect to such information; or (iv) which is or becomes publicly available through no breach of these Terms by the Receiving Party.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(b) The Receiving Party shall only use, disclose or otherwise process Confidential Information as set forth in these Terms. Each Party agrees to protect the confidentiality of the Confidential Information of the other in the same manner that it protects the confidentiality of its own proprietary and Confidential Information of like kind, but in no event shall either pParty exercise less than reasonable care in protecting such Confidential Information. Accessing Confidential Information through the Portal shall be restricted to Authorized Users. The Receiving Party shall not duplicate any material containing Confidential Information. The Receiving Party shall return or destroy all copies of materials containing Confidential Information upon reasonable request of the Disclosing Party or upon any earlier termination of these Terms for any reason whatsoever.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>(c) If the Receiving Party receives legal process for the Disclosing Party’s Confidential Information, the Receiving Party will first instruct the third party to request such Confidential Information from the Disclosing Party directly, unless the Receiving Party is prohibited by applicable law from doing so. In order to do so, the Receiving Party shall provide the Disclosing Party’s basic contact information to the third party.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART VII – DATA PRIVACY AND SECURITY&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Your Data&lt;/u>. If we are required to process Your personal information or other data to provide the Portal to You, You agree to provide all necessary rights and permissions for our processing of such personal information or data as described in these Terms and the applicable privacy policies in connection with your use of the Portal; (b) You represent and warrant to us that You have and shall maintain the legal rights and permissions to (w) provide us with access to &amp;nbsp;personal information or data; (x) permit us to use, disclose, and retain the personal information or data; (y) disclose the personal information or data for our business purposes; and (z) use the personal information or data in de-identified and/or aggregated form for analytical purposes in order to make public statements about the Portal and to improve the Portal as well as other products and services of Abbott and its Affiliates.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Portal Usage Data&lt;/u>. Abbott reserves all rights and interest in data related to usage of the Portal. Abbott may use such data to evaluate, protect and improve the performance of the Portal and other products and services.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>System of Record&lt;/u>. You acknowledge that the Portal should not be treated as a system of record. For clarity, we are not responsible for maintaining the data in accordance with any record retention requirements applicable to You under local, state, or federal law. We shall not have any obligation to retain, and may destroy, any or all data at any time, including upon the termination of these Terms.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Our Security Measures&lt;/u>&lt;em>. &lt;/em>We maintain administrative, technical, and physical measures to protect data from unauthorized access or disclosure. We do not warrant that the ACCESS AND USE OF THE PORTAL will be uninterrupted or error-free.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Transmissions&lt;/u>. We are not responsible or liable for any delays, delivery failures, or any other loss or damage resulting from the transfer of data over communications networks and facilities, including the internet, and You acknowledge that the PORTAL may be subject to limitations, delays and other problems inherent in the use of such communications facilities.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Your Security Measures&lt;/u>. &lt;a name=&quot;_Ref13559792&quot; id=&quot;_Ref13559792&quot;>&lt;/a>You agree to maintain reasonable and adequate administrative, technical, and physical measures to protect Your account access credentials for the Portal and all information and data on the Portal, from unauthorized access or use. You must promptly report security violations to us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:productsecurity@abbott.com&quot;>productsecurity@abbott.com&lt;/a> so that appropriate responsive actions may be taken.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART VIII – INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Proprietary Rights&lt;/u>. Abbott, its Affiliates, and/or its and their respective licensors own all right, title and interest in and to the Portal and any information and data contained therein (including the design, software code, scripts, database structures), including all copyrights, patents, trade secret rights, trademarks, and other intellectual property rights included in or utilized by the Portal (“&lt;strong>Portal IP&lt;/strong>”). You will not copy, reproduce, republish, upload, post, transmit, export or distribute in any way any Documents, material, documentation, or other information from or about the Portal or Portal IP without our prior written approval. You will not create derivative work, collective work, or compilation from, integrate with any other computer systems or programs, reverse engineer, decompile, disassemble, or otherwise attempt to discover the source code of the Portal IP or any software, hardware, components or other parts that make up the Portal IP&lt;em>. &lt;/em>If any Authorized User provides any ideas, suggestions, recommendations or concepts for improving or modifying the Portal or any related technology, then we will be free to use the same for any purpose and in any context with no compensation to You.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Reservation of Rights in Portal&lt;/u>. Subject to the limited rights expressly granted hereunder, we reserve all rights, title, and interest in and to the Portal and any Documents, information and data contained therein, including all related intellectual property rights. No rights are granted to You other than as expressly set forth herein.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Your Right to Use the Portal&lt;/u>. Subject to these Terms, we grant to You a limited, non-exclusive, revocable, non-sublicensable, non-transferable license to use the Portal, solely for the Organization’s internal operations to access and use the Documents as allowed under these Terms. Such license shall immediately expire upon termination of this Term as set forth herein, and such license is conditioned upon Your compliance with all Terms, violation of which automatically terminates the license.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART IX – INDEMNITY&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>To the fullest extent permissible by applicable law, You agree to defend, indemnify, and hold harmless Abbott, its Affiliates, and its and their respective officers, directors, agents, licensors, service providers, and representatives (“&lt;strong>Abbott Group&lt;/strong>”), from and against any actual or threatened dispute, claim, suit, action, demand, or proceeding (including, without limitation, a regulatory proceeding) by a third party (a “&lt;strong>Claim&lt;/strong>”) for any damages, fines, penalties, losses, or costs (including, without limitation, reasonable attorneys’ fees) (“&lt;strong>Liability&lt;/strong>”) arising from or related to Your breach of these Terms or violations of applicable law or Your negligence, recklessness, willful misconduct, any acts or omissions of your third-party suppliers, or any and all liability resulting from your use of Third Party Software.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Abbott shall provide the Organization written notice of a Claim against any of the Abbott Group within a reasonable time period (provided, however, that a delay in notification shall excuse Your defense and indemnification obligations only if, and only to the extent that, such delay materially prejudices the defense of such Claim). Notwithstanding Your obligation to defend Abbott Group against Claims as set forth in these Terms, Abbott shall have the right to exclusive control of the defense and settlement of the Claims and/or to select counsel to defend against and negotiate resolution of such Claims. You (including the Organization) shall give Abbott all reasonable assistance, at Your expense. You may not settle any Claim against the Abbott Group unless the settlement unconditionally and fully releases Abbott Group of all liability and fault and the Abbott Group have provided written consent to such settlement.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART X – DISCLAIMERS; LIMITATION OF LIABILITY&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Disclaimer of Warranties to You (including the Organization)&lt;/u>. We license access to the PORTAL and provide the PORTAL and all data and informatioN contained therein on an “as is” and “as available” basis, with no express or implied warranty of any kind. We do not make any warranties as to the timeliness, quality, availability, accuracy, usability, OR delivery of data submitted to us through the portal by or for you. The PORTAL is not designed or intended for use in environments requiring fail-safe performance&lt;em>. &lt;/em>You should not rely solely on the portal in any circumstance, including when the failure of the portal could lead to personal injury or death.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Disclaimer of Liability to You (including the Organization)&lt;/u>. To the fullest extent permitted by applicable law, in no event will Abbott Group be liable to you (or THE ORGANIZATION’S Affiliates, employees, contractors, or agents) or others for any indirect, special, incidental, exemplary, punitive, or consequential losses, costs, damages, penalties, charges or expenses of any kind arising out of or in connection with the portal or INFORMATION OR data contained therein, or these terms (whether in warranty, contract or tort, including negligence, or product liability, even if informed about the possibility thereof) including, without limitation, legal fees, loss of revenue or profits (whether direct or indirect), loss or interruption of business, or loss of goodwill, or any loss of use, loss, modification, inaccuracy, unavailability, or corruption of DATA, maintained, transmitted, or otherwise processed in connection with the portal.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Limitation of Liability to You (including the Organization)&lt;/u>. To the fullest extent permitted by applicable law, Abbott Group’s total aggregate liability to you AND THE ORGANIZATION’S Affiliates, Authorized Users, employees, contractors, agents, or others (including any liability for the acts or omissions of our AFFILIATES, employees, agents, licensors, consultants and subcontractors) arising out of or in connection with THESE TERMS or the PORTAL, whether in contract, tort (including negligence or breach of statutory duty), PRODUCTS LIABILITY, misrepresentation, restitution or otherwise shall be limited to attempting to fix any portal faults and, even if any loss was foreseeable or contemplated by the parties, shall not exceed one hundred U.S. dollars ($100)&lt;em>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART XI – ALTERNATIVE DISPUTE RESOLUTION&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>In the event that a dispute may arise relating to either Party's rights or obligations under these Terms, the Parties agree that any such dispute shall be resolved by the Alternative Dispute Resolution (&amp;quot;&lt;strong>ADR&lt;/strong>&amp;quot;) provisions set forth in Exhibit A attached hereto and incorporated herein by reference, the result of which shall be binding upon the Parties.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>PART XII – MISCELLANEOUS&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Notices&lt;/u>. We may provide notices to You under these terms by sending a message to the email address provided by You. Unless otherwise provided in these terms, you must provide notices to us by sending a message to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:productsecurity@abbott.com&quot;>productsecurity@abbott.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Entire Agreement; Amendments&lt;/u>. These Terms, including any additional terms or updates to these Terms that may be provided by Abbott from time to time, constitute the entire agreement between the Parties as it pertains to the access and use of the Portal and supersedes and extinguishes all previous agreements, promises, assurances, warranties, representations and understandings between the Parties as it pertains to access and use of the Portal, whether written or oral.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Independent Contractors&lt;/u>. The relationship between You and us is solely that of independent contractors and nothing in these Terms is intended to create a partnership or joint venture between You and us.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Assignment&lt;/u>. You are expressly prohibited from assigning any of Your rights or responsibilities under these Terms, including in the event any person or entity acquires all or substantially all of Organization’s applicable assets or business. Any such assignment without our prior written consent is null and void.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Third Party Beneficiaries&lt;/u>. Except as expressly stated in these Terms or as provided by applicable law, there are no third-party beneficiaries under these Terms.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Surviving Terms&lt;/u>&lt;em>. &lt;/em>Any provision of these Terms that should, by its nature, survive the termination of these Terms will survive.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Force Majeure Events&lt;/u>. If a Party is prevented from performing either its obligations or its purposes under these Terms by an act of God, public enemy, war, riot, disaster, storm, earthquake, other natural forces, by government order, decree or advisory, by public emergency, acts of government, floods, fires, earthquakes, civil unrest, acts of terror, pandemics, public health or other states of emergencies, strikes or other labor problems (other than those involving our employees), Internet service provider failures or delays, or denial of service attacks strike, significant curtailment of transportation systems or communications utilities, or by the intentional acts of anyone not a Party to these Terms (“&lt;strong>Force Majeure Event&lt;/strong>”), then that Party, upon written notice to the other, will be excused from that performance for the reasonable duration of that event.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>No Implied Waivers&lt;/u>&lt;em>. &lt;/em>The delay or failure of either Party to enforce at any time any of the provisions hereof shall not be a waiver of such provisions, any other provision, or of the right of such Party thereafter to enforce any provision hereof.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;u>Severability&lt;/u>. If, for any reason, a court with proper jurisdiction holds that any term or provision of these Terms is invalid or cannot be enforced, all other terms and provisions will remain in effect. The invalid or unenforceable term or provision will be reformed only to the extent necessary to make it valid and enforceable.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&lt;a name=&quot;_Ref21279871&quot; id=&quot;_Ref21279871&quot;>&lt;/a>&lt;u>Governing Law&lt;/u>. These terms and any dispute or claim arising out of or in connection with them or their subject matter or formation (including non-contractual disputes or claims) shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the State of Illinois, USA.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>[End of Standard Terms and Conditions of Use]&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>Exhibit A&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;h4>&lt;strong>Alternative Dispute Resolution&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Capitalized terms not defined in this Exhibit A shall have the meaning set forth in the Terms.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>To begin the ADR process, a Party first must send written notice of the dispute to the other Party for attempted resolution by good faith negotiations between their respective presidents (or their designees) of the affected subsidiaries, divisions, or business units within twenty-eight (28) days after such notice is received (all references to &amp;quot;days&amp;quot; in this ADR provision are to calendar days). If the matter has not been resolved within twenty-eight (28) days after the notice of dispute, or if the Parties fail to meet within such twenty-eight (28) days, either Party may initiate an ADR proceeding as provided herein. The Parties shall have the right to be represented by counsel in such a proceeding.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>1. To begin an ADR proceeding, a Party shall provide written notice to the other Party of the issues to be resolved by ADR. Within fourteen (14) days after its receipt of such notice, the other Party may, by written notice to the Party initiating the ADR, add additional issues to be resolved within the same ADR.&amp;nbsp;​&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>2. Within twenty-one (21) days following the initiation of the ADR proceeding, the Parties shall select a mutually acceptable independent, impartial and conflicts-free neutral to preside in the resolution of any disputes in this ADR proceeding. If the Parties are unable to agree on a mutually acceptable neutral within such period, each Party will select one independent, impartial, and conflicts-free neutral and those two neutrals will select a third independent, impartial and conflicts-free neutral within ten (10) days thereafter. None of the neutrals selected may be current or former employees, officers or directors of either Party or its Affiliates​.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>3. No earlier than twenty-eight (28) days or later than fifty-six (56) days after selection, the neutral(s) shall hold a hearing to resolve each of the issues identified by the Parties. The ADR proceeding shall take place at a location agreed upon by the Parties. If the Parties cannot agree on a location, the location shall be in Cook County, Illinois.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>4. At least seven (7) days prior to the hearing, each Party shall submit the following to the other Party and the neutral(s):&amp;nbsp;​&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>a) a copy of all exhibits on which such Party intends to rely in any oral or written presentation to the neutral;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>b) a list of any witnesses such Party intends to call at the hearing, and a short summary of the anticipated testimony of each witness;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>c) a proposed ruling on each issue to be resolved, together with a request for a specific damage award or other remedy for each issue. The proposed rulings and remedies shall not contain any recitation of the facts or any legal arguments and shall not exceed one (1) page per issue.&amp;nbsp;The Parties agree that neither side shall seek as part of its remedy any punitive damages.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>d) a brief in support of such Party's proposed rulings and remedies, provided that the brief shall not exceed twenty (20) pages. This page limitation shall apply regardless of the number of issues raised in the ADR proceeding.&amp;nbsp;​&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Except as expressly set forth in subparagraphs 4(a) - 4(d), no discovery shall be required or permitted by any means, including depositions, interrogatories, requests for admissions, or production of documents.​&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>5. The hearing shall be conducted on two (2) consecutive days and shall be governed by the following rules:&amp;nbsp;​&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>a) Each Party shall be entitled to five (5) hours of hearing time to present its case. The neutral shall determine whether each Party has had the five (5) hours to which it is entitled.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>b) Each Party shall be entitled, but not required, to make an opening statement, to present regular and rebuttal testimony, documents or other evidence, to cross-examine witnesses, and to make a closing argument. Cross-examination of witnesses shall occur immediately after their direct testimony, and cross-examination time shall be charged against the Party conducting the cross-examination.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>c) The Party initiating the ADR shall begin the hearing and, if it chooses to make an opening statement, shall address not only issues it raised but also any issues raised by the responding Party. The responding Party, if it chooses to make an opening statement, also shall address all issues raised in the ADR. Thereafter, the presentation of regular and rebuttal testimony and documents, other evidence, and closing arguments shall proceed in the same sequence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>d) Except when testifying, witnesses shall be excluded from the hearing until closing arguments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>e) Settlement negotiations, including any statements made therein, shall not be admissible under any circumstances. Affidavits prepared for purposes of the ADR hearing also shall not be admissible. As to all other matters, the neutral(s) shall have sole discretion regarding the admissibility of any evidence.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>6. Within seven (7) days following completion of the hearing, each Party may submit to the other Party and the neutral(s) a post-hearing brief in support of its proposed rulings and remedies, provided that such brief shall not contain or discuss any new evidence and shall not exceed ten (10) pages. This page limitation shall apply regardless of the number of issues raised in the ADR proceeding.​&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>7. The neutral(s) shall rule on each disputed issue within fourteen (14) days following completion of the hearing. Such ruling shall adopt in its entirety the proposed ruling and remedy of one of the Parties on each disputed issue but may adopt one Party's proposed rulings and remedies on some issues and the other Party's proposed rulings and remedies on other issues. The neutral(s) shall not issue any written opinion or otherwise explain the basis of the ruling.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>8. The neutral(s) shall be paid a reasonable fee plus expenses. These fees and expenses, along with the reasonable legal fees and expenses of the prevailing Party (including all expert witness fees and expenses), the fees and expenses of a court reporter, and any expenses for a hearing room, shall be paid as follows:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>a) If the neutral(s) rule(s) in favor of one Party on all disputed issues in the ADR, the losing Party shall pay 100% of such fees and expenses.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>b) If the neutral(s) rule(s) in favor of one Party on some issues and the other Party on other issues, the neutral(s) shall issue with the rulings a written determination as to how such fees and expenses shall be allocated between the Parties. The neutral(s) shall allocate fees and expenses in a way that bears a reasonable relationship to the outcome of the ADR, with the Party prevailing on more issues, or on issues of greater value or gravity, recovering a relatively larger share of its legal fees and expenses.​&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>9. The rulings of the neutral(s) and the allocation of fees and expenses shall be binding, non-reviewable, and non-appealable, and may be entered as a final judgment in any court having jurisdiction.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>10. Except as provided in paragraph 9 or as required by law, the existence of the dispute, any settlement negotiations, the ADR hearing, any submissions (including exhibits, testimony, proposed rulings, and briefs), and the rulings shall be deemed Confidential Information. The neutral(s) shall have the authority to impose sanctions for unauthorized disclosure of Confidential Information.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>11. All ADR hearings shall be conducted in the English language.​&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;"
                            textIsRich="true"/>
                    </var5-parsys1>
                </layoutcontainer>
            </responsivegrid>
        </root>
    </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
